Mss.B.F113 Mss.B.F113 Mss.B.F113
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, June 27, 1793; B F113; 8-3/4x7; Bicchierai, Alessandro, 1734-1797.
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the royal gallery.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], March 21, 1777; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Bicchierai, Alexxandro, 1734-1797.
    Florence, A.L.S. 3p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Comments on Priestley and his experiments on air. His praise of liberty. Remarks on European events.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Feb. 15, 1787; B F113; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Biencourt,
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning abolition of capital punishment in Tuscany.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Biffi-Tolomei, [Matteo
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Note of advice.
  - Letter to Leopoldo Fabbroni [Sic], Paris, Oct. 3, 1813; B F113; 9x7; Billi, Giuseppe
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his political duties. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], March 29, 1786; B F113; 11-1/2x7-1/2; Bissati,
    Turin, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for his letter.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Nov. 25, 1807; B F113; 9-1/4x8; Bobba, Charles
    A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Plans for travel. Publication. friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Feb. 28, 1808; B F113; 9x7; Bobba, Charles
    Alexandria, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Hopes to hear from him.
  - Letter to Mr. Wolrich Leeds, Feb. 5, 1778; B F113; 9x7; Born, [Jakob Heinrich?] von, 1750-1782.
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Fabroni.
  - Letter to [Anthony Shepherd?], London, July 12, 1778; B F113; 8-1/4x6-3/4; Boscovich, [Ruggero Giuseppe], 1711-1787.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Fabroni. Refers to Fontana. Printed: Théococidès. Trois lettres inedites de Boscovich.
  - Letter to [Anthony Shepherd], Aug. 30, 1778; B F113; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Boscovich, [Ruggero Guiseppe], 1711-1787.
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Printed: Theódoridès. Trois lettres inédites de Boscovich.
  - Letter to [Anthony Shepherd?;]., 1778; B F113; 3-1/4x7-1/4; Boscovich, Ruggero Giuseppe, 1711-1787.
    L. 1p. Incomplete. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Printed: Theódorides. Trois lettres inédites de Boscovich.
  - Letter to [Signor Pelli], Aug. 7, 1766; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Botta, [Moresciallo Alessandro, marchese
    A.L.in 3rd.p. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Notifies him that the duke wishes to speak with him.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], March 12, 1822; B F113; 12-3/4x8; Boulton Watt & Company.
    L. 3p. (see Fabroni papers) Concerning steam apparatus for minting money. On same sheet is letter from same to same; June 29, 1822.
  - Letter to J.[Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, June 29, 1822; B F113; 12-3/4x8; Boulton Watt & Company.
    L. 1p.and add. (see Fabroni papers.) Inquires as to certain points on the steam apparatus needed for minting money. On same page as copy of letter from same to same; March 12, 1822.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Paris, B F113; 6-1/4x4; Bourgoing, [Jean françois, baron de], 1748-1811.
    Paris, 25 Frimaire A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, April 23, 1802; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Bourke, Edmond, comte, 1761-1821.
    Rome, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Baron de Nolli, who will examine the property for its agricultural potential.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, May 7, 1802; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Bourke, Edmond, comte, 1761-1821.
    Rome, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) His plans for travelling, and his hopes to purchase in Florence.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, June 15, 1802; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Bourke, Edmond, comte, 1761-1821.
    Naples, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Cannot purchase the property at the price. Thanks for his assistance. Must go to Spain on the convoy and cannot return through Florence.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, April 16, 1802; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Bourke, Edmond, comte, 1761-1821.
    Rome, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the purchase of an estate in the environs of Florence.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Nov. 6, 1802; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Bourke, Edmond, conte, 1761-1821.
    Barcelona, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Is in Spain. Wishes to thank him again for his favors. Introduces Pinckney.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 10, 1802; B F113; 8-1/4x6; Bourke, Edmond, conte, 1761-1821.
    Valencia, A.L.S. 4p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Describes his trip from Naples to Spain. Describes Spain.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabroni, Florence, Aug. 28, 1797; B F113; 11-1/2x8; Brera, V[aleriano] L[uigi], 1772-1840.
    Pavia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Refers to Signor Nannoni, and expresses his regard for Fabroni.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, March 13, 1807; B F113; 9x7; Brongniart, Alex[andre], 1770-1847.
    Sevres, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (See Fabroni papers.) Thanks him for his favors. Will send his own book on mineralogy, and tells him where to reclaim it, in Florence.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Oct. 30, 1786; B F113; 4x6; Broussonet, [Pierre Marie Auguste], 1761-1817.
    Paris, A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Sends publication. Concerning agriculture.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni]., B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Broussonet, [Pierre Marie Auguste], 1761-1817.
    L.S. 3p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his publications on agriculture.
  - Letter to Jean Fabbroni, Florence, Feb. 7, 1790; B F113; 9-3/4x7; Brugnatelli, L[uigi Gasparo], 1761-1818.
    Pavia, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Jean Fabbroni, Florence, June 24, 1790; B F113; 9-1/2x7; Brugnatelli, L[uigi Gasparo], 1761-1818.
    Pavia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning material for his publication on chemistry.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni, Florence, Sept. 15, 1790; B F113; 9-3/4x7; Brugnatelli, L[uigi Gasparo], 1761-1818.
    Pavia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Publications for Annali Chemici. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni,Florence, November 18, 1790; B F113; 9-3/4x7; Brugnatelli, L[uigi Gasparo], 1761-1818.
    Pavia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for work on agriculture.
  - Letter to Jean Fabbroni, Florence, Feb. 1, 1793; B F113; 8-1/2x6-1/2x; Brugnatelli, L[uigi Gasparo], 1761-1818.
    Pavia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning an article for publication.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni,Florence, Nov. 13, 1815; B F113; 10-1/4x7; Brugnatelli, L[uigi Gasparo], 1761-1818.
    Pavia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning publications in the Journal of Physics.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, [Sept.?] 4, 1802; B F113; 10x7-1/4; Brunacci, [Vincenzo], 1768-1818.
    Milan, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces a man who travels to Tuscany.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Oct. 3, 1806; B F113; 9x7; Brunacci, [Vincenzo], 1768-1818.
    Milan, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning expenses.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, June 24, 1807; B F113; 10x7-1/4; Brunacci, [Vincenzo], 1768-1818.
    Pavia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces and recommends Luadei di Vicenza.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Oct. 17, 1810; B F113; 9-1/2x 7-1/4; Brunacci, [Vincenzo], 1768-1818.
    Milan, A.L.S. 2p.,add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers. ) Concerning his travels and people he has met.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Nov. 24, 1815; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Brunacci, [Vincenzo], 1768-1818.
    Pavia, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning mutual friends.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], April 4, 1804; B F113; 10x8-1/4; Bugge, [Thomas], 1740-1815.
    Copenhagen, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Smitten and Engelstost and praises them. Concerning Fabroni's work at the Florentine mint and states that Schimmelman in Copenhagan would like to know of it. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni]., B F113; 7-1/4x4-1/2; C[uvier], G[eorges Léopold Chrétien Frédéric Dagobert, baron], 1769-1832.
    A.L.S.with initials. 3p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his publications of fossils, etc. Scientific news. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, Aug. 22, 1794; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Caldini, Leopoldo M[arc] A[ntonio], 1725-1813.
    Padua, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Abildgaard. Refers to Fontana.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Paris, June 18, 1799; B F113; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Cambray, [Jacques], 1749-1807.
    Paris, 30 Pluviose an 7 []. A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Explains misunderstanding.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, June 8, 1799; B F113; 8-1/2x7; Cambry, [Jacques], 1749-1807.
    Paris, 20 Prairial an 7 []. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter. Thanks him for favor.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabrony [sic], Paris, March 6, 1799; B F113; 4x6; Cambry,[Jacques], 1749-1807.
    16 Ventose an 7 A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Invitation to tea.
  - Letter to Jean Fabbroni, Florence, April 24, 1800; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Carlisle, [Sir] Anthony, 1768-1840.
    London, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Answers his letter to Dr. Watson, who died five years ago. Anatomical discussion, and refers to Darwin.
  - Letter to Filippo Mazzei, Pisa, Nov. 20, 1811; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Carmignani, G[iovanni] A[lessandro], 1768-1847.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter. Refers to Fabroni.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, B F113; 9-1/2x7; Ceracchi, [Giuseppe], 1751-1801.
    Paris A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Cannot visit them.
  - Autograph., B F113; 2-1/2x3-1/4; Cerretti, Luigi, 1738-1808.
    A.D.S. 1p. (see Fabroni papers.)
  - Letter to Jean Fabbroni, Florence, Nov. 19, 1808; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Chaptal fills & A. Berthollet.
    Paris, L. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Costs of acids, etc.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni,Florence, Sept. 11, 1787; B F113; 8-3/4x7; Chaptal, [Jean Antoine Claude, comte,] 1756-1832.
    Montpellier, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Sends results of his study of water on vegetation.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, June 1, 1788; B F113; 7-3/4x6-1/4; Chaptal, [Jean Antoine Claude, comte,] 1756-1832.
    Montpellier, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter of scientific interest. Chemistry.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Jan. 10, 1810; B F113; 8-1/4x6; Chaptal, [Jean Antoine Claude, comte], 1756-1832.
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni]., B F113; 5x7-1/2; Chaptal, [Jean Antoine Claude, comte], 1756-1832.
    N.in 3rd.P. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic]., B F113; 6-1/4x6; Chaptal, [Jean Antoine Claude, comte], 1756-1832.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Asks for minerals.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, May 9, 1812; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Chaptel, [Jean Antoine Claude, comte], 1756-1832.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning scientific work.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Aug. 6, 1802; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Charles, [Jacques Alexandre César], 1746-1823.
    Vienne, A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) States that his case is being taken before the Emperor.
  - Statement that Leopoldo Fabbroni has studied experimental physics under him, July 14, 1799; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Charles, [Jacques Alexandre César], 1746-1823.
    Paris, 26 Messidor an 7 []. A.D.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.)
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni., B F113; 6x4; Chaumeton, [François Pierre], 1775-1819.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Called last night to borrow a book but he was out.
  - Letter to Leopoldo Pelli Fabbroni, Florence, Feb. 28, 1824; B F113; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Ciccolini, [Abbé] Lodovico, 1767-1854.
    Rome, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the Duchess of Devonshire's visit.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, July 12, 1801; B F113; 10x7-1/2; Ciccolini, L[odovico, conte, abbate], 1767-1854.
    Bologna, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Recommended a friend to contact him before going to Paris.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabroni, Florence, Aug. 27, 1803; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Cioni, G[aetano], 1760-1851.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning Quadri.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni., B F113; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Ciscár, Gabriel
    A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Is sorry they missed seeing each other. Suggests a place to visit.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 19, 1802; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Clark, H[enri Jacques Guillaume], 1765-1818.
    Florence, 28 Frimaire an 11 A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for his note on "la Republique de Leuques."
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, Dec. 6, 1801; B F113; 5-1/2x4; Clarke, [Henri Jacques Guillaume], 1765-1818.
    Florence, 15 Frimaire an 10 A.L. in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In French (see Fabroni papers.) Wishes to borrow a book.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Feb. 4, 1802; B F113; 7-1/2x7-1/4; Clarke, [Henri Jacques Guillaume], 1765-1818.
    Florence, Pluviose 19 an 10 L.in 3rd.P. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards prospectus for a literary journal of Paris.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], April 6, 1803; B F113; 6x3-3/4; Clarke, [Henri Jacques Guillaume], 1765-1818.
    16 Floreal an 11 L.in 3rd.P. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards prospectus for a new educational arrangement in Paris.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, Florence, July 5, 1803; B F113; 7-1/4x4-3/4; Clarke, [Henri Jacques Guillaume], 1765-1818.
    Florence, 16 Messidor an 11 L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Invitation to dinner.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Jan. 8, 1802; B F113; 8x6; Clarke, H[enri Jacques Guillaume], 1765-1818.
    Florence, 19 Nivose an 10 A.L.S. 1p. In French (see Fabroni paper.) Thanks for his prospectus on"thermolampes" and asks that he forward it to a friend.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Dec. 19, 1802; B F113; 7x5; Clarke, H[enri Jacques Guillaume], 1765-1818.
    Florence, 28 Frimaire an 11. L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Is too pressed for time to visit, but wishes information about "Lucques."
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], July 4, 1803; B F113; 8x6-1/4; Clarke, H[enri Jacques Guillaume], 1765-1818.
    Florence, 15 Messidor an 11 A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Fabroni Papers.) Finances.
  - Letter to Citoyen Cordo, March 25, 1804; B F113; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Colli, [Luigi Leonardo Gaspare Venanzio], 1760-1809.
    Bastia, 4 Germinal an 12 A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers. ) Information on a man.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Sept. 11, 1793; B F113; 9x7-1/4; Compton, Mr. & Mrs.
    Florence; L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add.,end. In French (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for his favors while visiting and aks for letters of recommendation.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Nov. 17, 1796; B F113; 9-1/ x7-1/4; Corsini, Neri
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Sends eloge on Redi. Concerning Fossombroni.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabrony, Florence, May 11, 1780; B F113; 8x6-1/2; Court de Gebelin, [Antoine], 1725-1784.
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Sends greetings and introduces Wygand.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, B F113; 8-1/2 x6-3/4; Court de Gebelin, [Antoine], 1725-1784.
    Florence. A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces two fellow-travellers.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], June 30, 1788; B F113; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Crell, L[orenz von
    Helmstadt in Brunswick, A.L.S. 3p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Wishes to correspond on scientific subjects. Reports on current scientific findings in Germany and Hungary.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, April 4, 1789; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Crell, L[orenz von
    Helmstedt, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Still has not received the books. Shipment of scientific publications to him.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, April 30, 1789; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Crell, L[orenz von
    Helmstadt, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) States how published items are to be shipped to him.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, March 4, 1790; B F113; 10-1/2x7-1/4; Crell, L[orenz von
    Helmstedt, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his publication and asks for payment for it. Concerning geology. Asks if he wishes to become a member of various German societies.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, May 14, 1790; B F113; 7-1/4x5-1/4; Crell, L[orenz von
    Helmstedt, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for payment. Wishes to acquire certain Italian publications.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], March 16, 1792; B F113; 9x7-1/4; Crell, L[orenz von
    Helmstadt, A.L.S. 3p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Chemistry. Concerning election to a learned society. His Annales...
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Oct. 4, 1793; B F113; 8-1/4x7-1/2; Crell, L[orenz von
    Helmstedt, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Memberships in learned academies. Wishes to hear from him, especially of news of physics and chemistry in Italy. Phlogiston.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Nov. 10, 1788; B F113; 9x7-1/4; Crell, L[orenzo von
    Helmstadt, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Scientific news of the day. Chemistry. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, April 1, 1820; B F113; 7-1/2x6-1/4; Cuvier, [Georges Léopold Chrétien Frédéric Dagobert], Baron, 1769-1832.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for fossil tooth. Concerning Brongniart. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Oct. 30, 1820; B F113; 10x8; Cuvier, [Georges Léopold Chrétien Frédéric Dagobert], baron, 1769-1832.
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Mr. Richie. Friendly letter
  - Letter to Leopoldo Pelli Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Aug. 8, 1824; B F113; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Cuvier, [Georges Léopold Chrétien Frédéric Dagobert],baron, 1769-1832.
    Paris, L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the medal he had struck in honor of his father.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Sept. 29, 1803; B F113; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Cuvier, G[eorges Léopold Chrétien Frédéric Dagobert, baron], 1769-1822.
    6 Vendémiaire an 12 A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Awaiting his work on quinine. Botany. Fossils. Mollusks. Refers to Fontana.
  - Letter to Jean [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Feb. 10, 1801; B F113; 8-1/4x6-1/2; Cuvier, G[eorges Léopold Chrétien Frédéric Dagobert, baron], 1769-1832.
    Paris, 21 Pluviose an 9 A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Fossil teeth. Concerning his work on fossils. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Oct. 9, 1801; B F113; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Cuvier, G[eorges Léopold Chrétien Frédéric Dagobert, baron], 1769-1832.
    Paris, 17 Vend. an 10. A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Thanks for his work and forwards his own. Scientific news. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Nov. 2, 1802; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Cuvier, G[eorges Léopold Chrétien Frédéric Dagobert, baron], 1769-1832.
    Paris, Brumair 11, IX L.S. 3p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter. Natural history.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, Jan. 6, 1803; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Cuvier, G[eorges Léopold Chrétien Frédéric Dagobert, baron], 1769-1832.
    6 Pluviose an 11 A.L.S. 3p.and add., end. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Prince Dolgorouki.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni [sic], Florence, B F113; 7-3/4x6; Cuvier, G[eorges Léopold Chrétien Frédéric Dagobert, baron], 1769-1832.
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces Mr. Armstrong(?). Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, July 18, 1800; B F113; 9x7-1/2; Czartoryski, A[dam Giorgio], prince, 1770-1861.
    Pisa, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Friendly letter concerning his visit to Italy.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabroni, Florence, Aug. 12, 1802; B F113; 10x7; Dandolo, [Vincenzo, conte], 1759-1819.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards gift. Thanks for having been made a member of the society.
  - Letter to [Adamo] Fabroni, Feb. 21, 1795; B F113; 9-1/2x6-3/4; Dandolo, [Vincenzo], 1759-1819.
    Venice, L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni Papers.) Concerning publications. Refers to Weigel.
  - Letter to Adam[o] Fabbroni, Florence, Feb. 28, 1795; B F113; 9-1/2x7; Dandolo, [Vincenzo], 1759-1819.
    Venice, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his publications. Refers to Weigel.
  - Letter to Gio[vanni] Fabbroni,Florence, Jan. 25, 1815; B F113; 10-1/4x7-1/2; Dandolo, [Vincenzo], 1759-1819.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards publication.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni,Florence, B F113; 10x7-1/2; Dandolo, [Vincenzo], 1759-1819.
    [A.L.S.] 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Sympathy over his wife.
  - Letter to Giovanni Fabbroni, Florence, B F113; 10x7-1/2; Dandolo, [Vincenzo], 1759-1819.
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Sends him facsimilie of an item.
  - Letter to Adam[o] Fabbroni, Florence, June 7, 1794; B F113; 9-1/4x6-3/4; Dandolo, Vinc[enz]o, 1759-1819.
    Venice, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning publications.
  - Letter to [Adamo Fabroni], July 30, 1791; B F113; 9-1/2x7; Dandolo, Vincenzo, 1759-1819.
    Venice, A.L.S. 2p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards his publication and discusses it.
  - Letter to [Adamo?] Giovanni, Sept. 17, 1791; B F113; 9-1/2x6-1/2; Dandolo, Vincenzo, 1759-1819.
    Venice, A.L.S. 1p. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Forwards publication by Lavoisier.
  - Letter to Adam[o] Fabbroni, Florence, Oct. 8, 1791; B F113; 9-1/4x6-3/4; Dandolo, Vincenzo, 1759-1819.
    Venice, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the publications on agriculture.
  - Letter to Adam[o] Fabbroni, Florence, Nov. 12, 1791; B F113; 9-1/4x7; Dandolo, Vincenzo, 1759-1819.
    Venice, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In Italian. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning his work on a dictionary.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabroni, B F113; 8x6-1/4; D'Arcet,
    A.L.S. 6p.and add. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Concerning the disposition of his father's fortune.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Fabroni], Nov. 15, 1787; B F113; 7-3/4x6; D'Arcet, [Jean Pierre Joseph], 1774-1844.
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. In French. (see Fabroni papers.) Introduces a young doctor.
  - Letter to [Giovanni] Fabbroni, Nov. 23, 1798; B F113; 8-1/2x6-1/2; D'Arcet, [Jean Pierre Joseph], 1774-1844.